http://www.permaculture.co.uk/policies

Policies | Permaculture magazine
Jump to navigation
log in register
Select LanguageEnglishAfrikaansAlbanianArabicArmenianAzerbaijaniBasqueBelarusianBulgarianCatalanChinese (Simplified)Chinese (Traditional)CroatianCzechDanishDutchEstonianFilipinoFinnishFrenchGalicianGeorgianGermanGreekHaitian CreoleHebrewHindiHungarianIcelandicIndonesianIrishItalianJapaneseKoreanLatvianLithuanianMacedonianMalayMalteseNorwegianPersianPolishPortugueseRomanianRussianSerbianSlovakSlovenianSpanishSwahiliSwedishThaiTurkishUkrainianUrduVietnameseWelshYiddish
GiftDonateSubscribe
Search form
Search
HomeMagazinePM Current and back issuesPM SubscribeFeaturesWhat is Permaculture?ArticlesWriter's blogBook and Product ReviewsSolutionsVideosLiving With the Land seriesPodcastsCoursesPermaculture Design Courses (PDC)Introductory coursesSpecial coursesEventsClassifiedsAccomodationCoursesDesign servicesEventsFor saleGeneralHolidaysOpportunitiesPersonalProperty & landTrades & craftsWantedPublicationsShop
You are hereHome ›› ABOUT ››
Advertisement
Policies
Privacy Policy
Important information about who we are
We are:
Hyden House Ltd
Permaculture Magazine
Permanent Publications
Permaculture Market
Your privacy is important to us. This privacy statement explains what personal data we collect from you and how we use it.
Controller
Hyden House Ltd is the data controller/data processor for your personal information
Contact details
If you have any questions about this privacy policy or how to exercise your legal rights you can contact us at the following
Post:
SubscriptionsHyden House LtdThe Sustainability CentreDroxford RoadEast MeonHantsGU32 1HR
Tel: 01730 776582
Email: subscriptions@permaculture.co.uk
What information we collect and store
Personal data, or personal information, means any information about a person from which that person can be identified.  It does not include anonymous data where the identity has been removed.
Identity data includes first name, last name, and job title.Contact data includes billing and delivery address, email address and telephone number.Transaction data includes products you have ordered from us.Financial data includes your payment details for orders received via post, phone and the Internet
Orders sent from Permaculture Magazine, Permanent Publications and Permaculture Market to our distributors do not include your financial data.  These payment transactions are processed securely by our payment gateway and your financial details are not stored.
You can sign into your account online to see any personably identifiable information we have stored about you. If you believe the information is wrong and wish to have it changed please contact us. You can also email us for this information.
How is your personal data collected?
Telephone orders directly with our subscriptions department
Via email from you
Via our online shop - https://shop.permaculture.co.uk
Via letter
In person at events
How we use your personal information
We will only use your personal data in accordance with the law.  We use your personal data in the following circumstances:
We will use your personal data when we need to perform the contract we have entered into with you and where we have your consent e.g. when you purchase a magazine subscription from us and we need to use your identity and contact information to process and deliver your order.
Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interests and rights do not override those interests.
Where we need to comply with legal and regulatory obligations.
We use technologies like cookies (small files stored by your browser), to anonymously identify your computer or device so we can deliver a better experience. Our systems also log information like your browser, operating system and IP address.Our systems are not designed to associate personal information with your activities (such as pages you view or things you click on or search for).We do not knowingly contact or collect personal information from children under 13. If you believe we have inadvertently collected such information, please contact us so we can promptly obtain parental consent or remove the information.Our service does not currently recognize the "Do Not Track" signal that may be available in some web browsers.
We do not use or collect your precise geographic location.
Change of purpose
We will only use your personal data in accordance with the purpose for which we collected it unless we reasonably consider that we need to use it for another purpose that is compatible with the original purpose.
You have the right to withdraw consent to marketing at any time by contacting us at subscriptions@permaculture.co.uk
Disclosures of your personal details
We will pass on your personal data to the distributor /supplier of the product you have ordered and to the supply chain partner who will deliver the product to you.
The personal data we disclose to third parties includes your name, address, e-mail address, telephone number, transaction and marketing data.  We do not disclose your financial data.
We generally do not share personally identifiable information (such as name, address, email or phone) with other companies for marketing purposes.
We do not allow advertising companies to collect data through our service for ad targeting.
Data retention
We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purpose we are collecting it for. In addition we are required to retain your personal data for legal and accounting requirements.
We will keep your personal data for three years after your last transaction with us.
Your legal rights
Right to access your personal dataRight to correct your personal dataRequest erasure of your personal dataRequest to transfer your personal dataRight to opt outRight to withdraw consentRight to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority
If you wish to exercise any of the rights set out above please contact us at subscriptions@permaculture.co.uk
In the UK the supervisory authority can be contacted at https://ico.org.uk
Access to your personal data
You do not have to pay a fee to access your personal data or to exercise any of your other rights.  However we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive.  Alternatively we may also refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.
In order to supply personal data we may need to request specific information from you to confirm your identity and your to right to access the personal data you are requesting.  This measure is designed to ensure personal data is not disclosed to any person who does not have the right to see or request it.
We will respond to all legitimate requests within one month.
Our third parties
In order to serve you, we will share your personal and anonymous information with our suppliers and distributors. Their use of information is limited to these purposes, and subject to agreements that require them to keep the information confidential.
Our service providers have assured us that they take reasonable steps to safeguard the data they hold on our behalf.
Our third party suppliers are listed below
Orca Book Services Ltd - www.orcabookservices.co.ukMarsden Book Services Ltd - www.marston.co.ukSelect Publishers - selectps.co.ukInk Distribution - www.inkdistribution.co.ukDisticor Magazine Distribution Services - www.disticor.comNetherton Foundry - www.netherton-foundry.co.ukRoyal Mail - www.royalmail.com/privacy-noticeInterparcel - https://uk.interparcel.com/privacyThomas Flinn - www.flinn-garlick-saws.co.ukSimon Fairlee - www.thescytheshop.co.ukEcozoom - www.ecozoom.comImplementations - www.implementations.co.ukChillington Tools - www.chillingtontoolsonline.co.ukHotbins Bins Composting - www.hotbincomposting.comWarner Midlands (Printers) -  www.warners.co.uk
Security
We take all reasonable steps to secure your personally identifiable information against unauthorized access or disclosure. We encrypt the transmission of data on pages where you provide payment information.
However, no security or encryption method can be 100% guaranteed to protect information.
Changes to PolicyThis privacy policy was last updated MARCH 2020. Our privacy policy may change from time to time. If we make any material changes to our policies, we will place a prominent notice on the website. If the change materially affects registered users, we will send a notice to you by email, push notification or text.
Cookies policy for www.permaculture.co.uk
Permaculture.co.uk uses cookies. Cookies aren't, in fact, biscuits, but actually very small amounts of text that are stored on your computer when you visit a website. Almost every site on the web uses them, from Google to the BBC. They help make your visit a more enjoyable and secure experience - they allow us to remember if you are logged in to the website, and mean that we can avoid pestering you with promotions and requests to which you have already signed up.
We store no personally identifiable data in cookies - they are just a string of garbled numbers and letters - and they are not capable of harming your computer in any way.
Like most other sites on the web, we use Google Analytics to get an idea of how many people are visiting our site, from where, and what they read when they get here. It helps us make our articles more useful and interesting to you. The data that we receive back from Google is totally anonymised and contains no personal information.
Some of the companies that advertise on our site may track your browsing habits in order to show you more relevant adverts. You may choose to block this behaviour by visiting http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp.
So why are we telling you this? An EU directive means that regulations on cookies have been tightened up, and we wanted to be completely upfront with our readers about what is happening when you visit our website.
Revised March 2020
Advertisement
ABOUT
The team
Our writers
Privacy
Contact us
SUPPORT OUR WORK
Instagram
The material on this website is copyright 2015. You have the right to view these pages and where applicable, to copy these pages and any images to a cache for reference by yourself only at a later date. You are not granted any other rights and the Web site owner reserves all other rights.The opinions expressed on this website are not necessarily those of the publisher, Hyden House Ltd, and whilst we take every care in checking the validity of information presented here, we cannot accept any responsibility for its accuracy or any liability for any form of damages incurred by the use of such information.
